Think of all the little girls
who could have been saved
if our government had acted on that
information in 1996. [music]
Hundreds of little girls
could have been saved from getting
[music] molested if our government had
acted on that information.
Hi, I'm John Keryaku and welcome back to
Deep Focus. We're in the midst of a
breaking story related to the Epstein
documents. A couple of weeks ago,
Congress passed a a law. There was some
drama around the law because it seems
like the Republican leadership in the
House didn't want to address the
situation. There was a discharge
petition. Democrats jumped on it, etc.,
etc.
The administration was forced then once
the president signed the thing into law
to release
all of the Jeffrey Epstein documents.
Now, we know we're probably not going to
see all of the Jeffrey Epstein
documents. We probably are going to see
redacted versions of some or most or
many or some other descriptive word of
the Epstein documents. But they're being
released in tranches right now. In fact,
just minutes before we started this
interview, there was another release of
several thousand pages of documents. You
can go on to justice.gov
and search them and read them for
yourself. They may not make a whole lot
of sense if you don't have a deep
understanding of the background uh to
this case. I actually don't have the
deepest understanding, but our our guest
sure does. Nick Bryant has been
following this case from the very very
beginning. He's an investigative
journalist and the author of several
books. I think uh one of the most
important of which was uh the Franklin
Scandal, the story of power brokers,
child abuse, and betrayal. Nick, thanks
so much for joining us.
>> Great to be with you, John.
>> Glad to have you back. Very glad to have
you back because this is a serious
story. It's breaking news. After the
first trunch of documents was released a
couple of days ago, people weren't happy
because they expected so much more. In
addition to a couple of screw-ups, one
of which was that on the redacted
documents, if you highlight the
redactions, cut them, and then paste
them into a new document, they unredact
themselves, and you can read what was
redacted. Well, what was redacted was
the names of the victims. And so now the
names of the victims are all out there
whether whether the victims authorized
them to be or not and we have that to
deal with now on top of the actual
information that's being released. So
first if you don't mind starting us off
with your thoughts on the way things are
going and your thoughts about what what
it is that's new that we're learning
about Jeffrey Epstein and what he did.
the the Trump administration is actually
breaking the law at this point.
On Friday, they were supposed to have
documents
in full and the only redactions would be
redactions that are related to national
security, which I still have a hard time
comprehending what a bunch of child
molesters have to do with national
security. But that aside,
there should have been much more
information released. And at this point,
they're saying the Trump administration
is saying that 5% have been released.
But there was 200
people in the Department of Justice that
were working on this for a month. You
would think that there would be more
than 4,000 documents that would be
released.
And again, you talked about
victims being their names being out
there. I mean, there were victim their
names were being out there without the
redactions. So, and of course, all the
perpetrators are redacted.
It really it's not to the spirit or the
letter of the law. The Epstein Victims
Trans Epstein Files Transparency Act was
very definitive about what the Trump
administration was supposed to deliver
last Friday and it has not. And I think
that it's just going to be a slow drip
and Donald Trump is actually this
morning he was attacking Thomas Massie.
He was saying that Bill Clinton was a
good guy and he hated to release all
these pictures of Bill Clinton and that
Thomas Massie was a scumbag. Thomas
Massie is simply a guy that wants to
make sure that child molesters don't get
away with molesting children with
impunity. I mean, that's that's
basically what he wants. And I think
that the vast majority of American
[clears throat] the vast majority of
Americans agree with that. But yet our
president doesn't seem to feel that that
is baseline decency.
>> I have to say too, I was struck by this
letter that Epstein wrote to Larry
Nassar, Dr. Larry Nisar, who was
convicted of dozens and dozens, maybe
hundreds of counts of child molestation
and sexual abuse. He was the doctor for
the women's gymnastics team, the US
Olympic team. Um, and he says, you know,
by the time you receive this, I would
have I I will have gone home by now. Uh,
and then he just goes on to blame
everything on on Donald Trump of all
things. What do you make of that? Or or
maybe even more importantly, what what
should the country make of that?
Epstein obviously had a lot of antipathy
towards Donald Trump
and those emails were I mean Epstein is
calling Trump the worst scumbag he's
ever met which
I mean Epstein was very far from a
paragon of morality. Um actually I think
he was a psychopath. So I think that uh
is the kettle calling the pot black when
Jeffrey Epstein is accusing Donald Trump
of being a scumbag? I and those emails
also show now Donald Trump says that he
severed his friendship with Jeffrey
Epstein in 2003 2004 and those emails
show that their friendship continued
and I think that Trump has
a lot to ask for. You know what he's
done is kept this covered up and now
he's breaking the law in furtherance of
the cover up. So Donald Trump has a lot
to explain for himself. I just don't
understand, Nick.
I don't understand what goes into a
decision to vi to violate a law that
that he championed, right? He campaigned
on the idea of releasing all of the
Epstein documents. And so what what's
the delay if if you know if you are
confident that you have done nothing
wrong
and we already know that you know Bill
Gates is implicated in these documents
and Bill Clinton and Prince Andrew and a
whole host of other people Nam Chomsky a
whole bunch of people.
If you're confident that you're not, I I
just don't see any reason to not release
everything. Am I missing something? Am I
being naive? Or is Donald Trump likely
implicated in these documents?
>> Well, the thing about Jeffrey Epstein is
he was a pedophilic pimp amongst other
things. I mean, he was a multi-talented
guy. He was a pedophilic pimp. He was a
money launderer. And actually he was uh
fairly astute at being a war propheter
too which we we can get into in a little
bit. But um
with
what Trump Trump did everything he
possibly could to put the kibash on that
discharge petition. Everything. I mean
and Mike Johnson adjourned Congress
early and he wouldn't swear in the
representative from Arizona. That would
have given the discharge position 218
votes which would have ultimately put
made the House vote on it and then it
would have been sent to Jonathan the
Senate majority leader and he could have
quashed it right there and he sounded
very cynical towards it but then all of
a sudden I think that they the
administration realized that that
discharge tradition had become a
tsunami.
>> Yeah. And 89% of the American public
wanted, according to the CBS poll, 89%
of the American public wanted to see
transparency.
So there was a tremendous amount of
pressure on Trump and then he signed the
Epstein Viles Transparency Act, which
gave him which gave the Department of
Justice 30 days. And it's been very
obvious to anybody that's really
following this story that that
administration didn't take it very
seriously or they're doing everything
they can. I mean, but the Trump
administration has done everything it
can to delay delay delay and cover up
and cover up and cover up. So obviously
if Donald Trump doesn't have something
to hide, there are some very powerful
people
that are putting pressure on him to make
sure that it's covered up. Or maybe uh
an intelligence agency that's always
entirely possible through him,
>> right? I want to get to that, too.
First, I want to read you um a uh a
couple of sentences from a piece at ABC
News that was uh released about an hour
ago. It says, "A group of alleged
victims of Jeffrey Epstein accused the
Department of Justice of missteps,
including violations of the law in its
partial release of files related to the
disgraced financeers's abuse of young
women and girls. The DOJ faced a Friday
deadline imposed by Congress to release
a massive cache of records gathered
during government investigations into
the sex offender. Justice officials
released thousands of files ranging from
investigative documents to grand jury
testimony to snapshots taken by Epstein
and his friends, but said that it would
fail to fully release all the files by
the deadline. Okay, we've seen a lot of
reporting already just in the last 48
hours
focused on these snapshots. We've all
now seen the gross picture of Bill
Clinton in a hot tub and uh Prince
Andrew laying across, you know, the laps
of five young women.
What about things like grand jury
testimony, which is normally offlimits
to absolutely everybody? What about
these investigative files? Are we
learning anything new about this case?
There's one thing that we have learned
that has been [clears throat]
I think exceedingly auspicious is Maria
Farmer said that she went to the FBI in
1996 and reported Jeffrey Epstein and
there was a New York police report that
I eventually found where she did go to
the New York uh NYPD and made a report,
but the report said that Epstein was
threatening to burn one of her pains.
that didn't talk about anything else
that Epstein was up to, but the FBI
report from 1996 shows that she did talk
to them about uh Epstein had taken
pictures of Maria and Maria had taken
those pictures of her sisters because
she's an artist and she wanted to
give artistic renditions of her younger
sisters and Epstein took them and then
threatened to burn her house down and
was very malicious and according to the
FBI right on the header of the
investigation is child pornography.
So Epstein was reported for child
pornography in 1996 or the FBI certainly
knew about it because
we know that the Bush administration
started the cover up with the sweetheart
deal and then it went through Obama,
Biden, Trump and then uh and then Trump
again. But now we know that the Clinton
FBI Department of Justice was aware of
Epstein. And of course at that time
Jeffrey Epste was bringing young women,
not girls but young women into the White
House for Bill Clinton. We we know that.
So I think that the Jeffrey Epstein
coverup was started at the federal level
from probably 1996. That's I think been
the most revelatory of the documents
that have come out is that
the FBI could have put the kab and the
department of justice could have put the
kibash on Jeffrey Epstein 1996. Now,
think of all the little girls
who could have been saved
if our government had acted on that
information in 1996. Hundreds of little
girls
could have been saved from getting
molested if our government had acted on
that information.
>> I wanted to ask you too about
specifically about the grand jury um
minutes.
Two different federal judges ordered
that the grand jury minutes be released.
That's very unusual. Grand juries are
usually completely secret. The sessions
are secret. The findings are secret. But
two different federal judges ordered
that they be released. There was a
trunch of 119 pages in this most recent
release. They were all grand jury
minutes and every single word was
blacked out. Why do you think that is?
We would have expected, of course, the
names of the victims, maybe the names of
the alleged perpetrators to be blacked
out, but every single word. Why? Why is
that?
>> Uh, obviously the Department of Justice
didn't really want us to know what went
on in that grand jury. There was a very
corrupt state grand jury that found that
Jeffrey Epstein hadn't molested a single
child. It was the special prosecutor was
Lannab Balovic and and actually Ronda
Santis, the governor of Florida,
released the transcripts of that grand
jury. And I've dissected it. It's on the
web the director of an organization.
It's called Epstein Justice. and your
audience can go to our website and look
at the video I made on that grand jury
where I basically show how corrupted
that grand jury is to the point where
at that point the Palm Beach Police
Department were aware of I think at
least 20 victims and they had the
statements of five and only two of those
victims were called to testify and they
were skewered by Label Lavik and
Actually, one of them was one of them
was called a prostitute.
>> Oh my god.
>> She she was started getting molested by
Jeffrey Epstein when she was 16 and she
was now 18. And the other one had been
molested by Jeffrey Epste when she was
14 and now she was 16. So they were
pretty easy for her to just completely
malign, which is very unfortunate. But
according to all the sources really, the
the feds initially had a 50 or 60 count
indictment against Jeffrey Abste.
>> I didn't know that.
>> And that's what's been covered up big
time.
There is documents about that
investigation, but they're heavily
redacted, too. So
there's so much that I mean that
investigation by the FBI,
it could have easily just redacted the
victim's names and but everything was
redacted. I don't know why the
Department of Justice redacted the
entire grand jury, but that was I mean
that goes against the law. As I said
earlier, the Trump administration is
breaking a law. A law that Donald Trump
signed, a law that every senator voted
for, a law that 434
representatives voted for. So in
Congress, there was one individual that
abstained from voting yes for that law
and Donald Trump signed it into law and
now they're the administration is
completely reneging on and and Pam Bondi
is completely charged credibility and so
is Cash Patel. They stood before the
Senate and House and said that not a
single child have been trafficked and we
obviously know better. We knew better
before this transfer of documents was
we knew this years ago that Jeffrey
Epstein was trafficking underage girls
and for them to come out it's really uh
it it shows you
how our government has really descended
into something that's that's horrific
because
with sexual abuse survivors and I've
been researching and writing about child
sexual abuse for 22 23 years. And
the best thing that you can say to a
survivor is
I believe you.
The worst thing that you can say to a
survivor or a victim is I don't believe
you. And that's what the Trump
administration's been saying to all
these victims. And they're conceding
that it's initially they said a
thousand. Now they're saying 1,200. So
all those girls were when Cash Patel and
Pam Bonnie were before the Senate and
the House saying that no one was
trafficked. I mean basically our two top
law enforcement officers in the country
were saying to all those girls, we don't
believe you.
>> Right. Nick, did you expect to see any
information released? And not all the
information has been released, we should
point out, but did you expect to see by
now some information that might help to
explain why it was that Epstein got the
sweetheart deal that he did way back in
2006?
All that has either been redacted or it
hasn't been released
because there was a very intense
investigation into Epstein
and that somewhere along the line just
completely got quashed
and
the investigative documents from the FBI
that we have as I said earlier have have
been redacted. So
it's
obvious to me that what's going on now
is a cover up.
It's it's it's a cover up. And if Donald
Trump isn't protecting himself, he's
protecting other entities and other
people. Yeah. And that that is just
that's just inexplicable to me because
this is one of those like
no way to lose situations provided that
you're clean in the first place. But if
you're clean in the first place and
everybody wants this information
released besides the fact that your
base, your political base has this as
one of its top issues, right? to the
point where he had to campaign on the
issue. If elected, I will release all of
the Epstein documents and then you're in
a position
to release the documents.
Your base force is Congress's hand. They
give you 30 days to do it and then you
do it in fits and starts. You redact a
whole lot of stuff. You don't really add
any information to the body of evidence
that's already out there. I just don't
see what the endgame is. Help me
understand the politics of this. What
What is he trying to accomplish?
>> The only thing I can think of is delay,
delay, delay. But he's going to be
president for another three years. I
mean, theoretically anyway.
So, there's only going to be so much he
can delay. And like I said, according to
the Department of Justice,
only four to 5% of those documents have
been released.
And
as I also said earlier, there were 200
lawyers at the Department of Justice
vetting those documents.
How you you had 200 lawyers
and there was 4,000
pages of new documents that released and
200 lawyers had a month to vet. You
would think that they would have
accomplished more. Maybe they just
needed higher potency coffee or
something, but um it at at this point
it's very much a cover up. And and
actually it's breaking the law, too.
We saw something like this in the Nixon
administration.
And I think what is going on is
obstruction of justice. And that's
ultimately what got Nixon impeached was
obstruction of justice. Well, you know
what they say. It's never the crime that
does politicians in. It's the cover up
of the crime.
>> That's what didn't that's what did in
Nixon and everybody around him.
>> It was the cover up.
>> And actually Nixon didn't even know that
the crime had been committed. He just it
was just his a leopard doesn't change
his spots. He just saw some a problem
and just saw it had to be covered up
even though he didn't know the genesis
of it. With Donald Trump, it's a little
bit different because this has played
out in front of our entire country. Um
the the way that Donald Trump is he was
calling it a hoax and it's just been
pretty pretty, as I said, horrific that
our government has descended to what
it's descended to. I mean, child sexual
abuse is the most heinous of crimes.
The most heinous of crimes. And the way
our government is so blatantly
involved in covering it up in
obstruction, it's it's actually it's
it's sickening.
>> Nick, I'll tell you. I've said on other
podcasts over the years that fully
onethird of the of the inmates in the
prison where I served 23 months after I
blew the whistle in the CI torture
program, fully 35% of them were
convicted pedophiles. They were sort of
divided between what we called clickers,
those who just looked at pictures of of
children, and touchers, people who had
actually traveled across state lines to
molest children. The sentences that
these guys had were draconian and
rightfully so. We're talking about
people in a low security prison. They
can't go to minimum because they'll
abscond, but they can't go to a medium
or a maximum because they'll get killed
there, right? people will beat them to
death. Uh so they're all in low security
prisons. Well,
if if it's if it's pro-forma to sentence
a convicted pedophile to 20, 25, 30, I
knew one who was in for 60 years.
I just simply don't understand
why we're looking at Jeffrey Epstein in
a different way even after death.
I just don't understand why the effort
to maybe not protect his legacy, but to
be careful not to try to soil his legacy
any more than he [snorts] had already
soiled it. Can you help me understand
this? I don't get why why the necessity
for this protection.
>> I don't think it's about protecting
Jeffrey Epstein at this point. I think
it's about protecting
a a way of life, political system. It's
protecting a political system and it's
protecting some powerful people that are
part of that system.
That's what that's what the protection
is about now. And
with or without Jeffrey Epstein, it was
very obvious, and we saw this in 1996,
we saw it again in uh 2008 with the
feds. It's it's very obvious that
Jeffrey Epste was going to be protected,
but it was the reason the reason why
Jeffrey Epste was going to be protected
is because what he was plugged into.
I'm going to take a very short break uh
for a word from our our sponsors who
were very grateful to have by the way
before we get into this this next half
of our conversation with Nick Bryan
about Jeffrey Epstein and the documents.
And while you're distracted by these uh
by these Epstein headlines, much like I
am, a real transformation is underway,
that's the rise of the digital dollar.
134 countries, including the United
States, are developing central bank
digital currencies. That means your
transactions can be tracked, your
spending can be controlled, your savings
might be vulnerable to instant freezing.
This is what the current public policy
is moving toward. bureaucrats and those
suspicious former colleagues of mine in
our nation's three-letter agencies would
love nothing more than to have more
information about you, about your
spending, and about your habits. The
government calls it innovation, but
let's call it what it really is. It's
financial surveillance. Well, American
Alternative Assets has put together a
free guide that shows you how to protect
your retirement with physical gold. It's
called the digital dollar trap and it's
something that every freedomminded
American should be reading. Inside the
free guide, you'll discover how to
protect yourself from government
overreach with physical assets like gold
and silver. So go to johnlovesgold.com
right now to get this completely free
guide. That's johnloves.com
because if the dollar is going digital,
you're going to need something real.
Um, Nick, I want to turn if we could to
Gain Maxwell.
This bothers me. This whole situation
with Galain Maxwell bothers me very,
very much. She's a convicted pedophile.
Number one, let's just call a spade a
spade here. She wasn't Jeffrey Epstein's
girlfriend. It was associated blah blah
blah blah. She's a convicted pedophile
and she has 20some years in prison to
show for it. But I'll tell you what
bothers me. Number one,
she was brought from her prison to
Washington DC to testify before a grand
jury and to uh have a conversation with
investigators.
Great.
But then just a few days later, she was
transferred from a low security prison
where all the pedophiles are kept to a
minimum security work camp. That just
doesn't happen. If you're a pedophile,
you go to the actual prison. She went to
the minimum security work camp where
she's able to walk the beach and pick up
trash and do whatever it is that you
know minimum security people do. They're
barely under guard as it is. Then she
applied for some sort of relief. We're
not 100% sure. We don't know if it's
either a pardon or a commutation, both
of which would would allow her just to
go straight home and live happily ever
after.
Why are we even having this
conversation? Do you think Do you think
it's possible that she could give the
Justice Department enough new
information to warrant a commutation or
a pardon? Is this something that Donald
Trump is actually considering, do you
think? Where do you see this going?
>> I don't know. uh the information that
she gave Todd Blanch, I mean the crux of
it was Donald Trump wasn't involved with
Jeffrey Epstein
and that's what enabled her to go to
this minimum security prison in uh Texas
and and work on her yoga as
was the upshot is she exonerated Donald
Trump and I really hope
that Donald Trump does not give her a
pardon. She appealed her case on the
fact that all of Epstein's
co-conspirators have been given immunity
by the Southern District of Florida in
2007208
and which is I I have that document.
It's kind of a unbelievably
mind-boggling document.
And
because she was given immunity in the
Southern District, she felt like she was
given immunity, categorical immunity in
all districts.
And that often happens with mafia turn
codes. They're given immunity in one
district and that applies to all
districts. So her actually her attorneys
had a fairly solid foundation to argue
for her because
the Southern District of New York came
after her after she had been given
immunity by the Southern District of
Florida.
But the Supreme Court opted not to hear
her case. Her case was appealed all the
way up to the Supreme Court and the
Supreme Court opted not to appeal her or
opted not to hear her case. So
according to our laws and our appellet
mechanisms, she [snorts] is not entitled
to get any kind of a break at this
point. I mean, it's already it's been
argued up to the Supreme Court. So if
Donald Trump has made some kind of
underhanded deal with her,
some kind of subrosa deal with her, that
would be that that would just be really
really
>> really bad.
>> I mean I Yeah. I just uh
>> Yeah. and and and then think about all
the the victims of Gain Maxwell that are
out there and and
I've talked to some of them and there's
they're still very much frightened of
Gain Maxwell.
>> Well, we know the American Psychological
Association and the American Psychiatric
Association are crystal clear over the
fact that pedophiles cannot be reformed.
It's not possible. their brains can't be
cured of of pedophilia.
So, society needs to be protected from
them. That's why we have such long
sentences for these crimes. And I it
doesn't surprise me one bit that these
that these women are afraid of Gain
Maxwell. She's a monster and society
needs to be protected from her. So, I
think that they've they've got, you
know, they've got something to say that
the country should listen to because if
she were to be freed, whether through
commutation or or pardon,
I I would fear for my children,
literally.
And it would be such an egregious a v
violation against all the victims that
she molested and trafficked over there
because if you look at the documentation
she was actually I think more vicious
than Jeffrey Epstein human traffickers
and that's the media has let down these
Epstein victims in multiple ways but one
of the major ways is the media has not
really delineated
just how vicious these people are. And
there's been a couple of books that have
been written by Epstein survivors. One
was called uh one was by Sarah Ransom
and the other one is by Virginia Gree,
nobody's girl, which just came out. And
and those books really show what
psychopaths
Maxwell and Epstein were. I mean, they
they they are psychopaths. And I would
just be stunned if she got pardoned or a
commutation.
For her to be in that prison in Texas
now is an incredible violation of
American juristprudence. She should not
be allowed to be in that Texas prison.
And actually when she was put in the
first prison in uh in Florida, they
bumped her up to dormatory living very
quickly. And usually inmates that are
bumped up to dormatory living, they
they've been there for a while and
they've been exemplary prisoners and
they're coming close to their release
date. But she was bumped up to uh donor
living very very quickly which is
another miscarriage of justice in the
Glenn Maxwell story.
>> Yeah. I just don't I just don't
understand it at all. You know, we we
talk about uh we talk about um
psychological therapy for people with
this kind of predeliction
and we talk about on the other side
um community incarceration where after
they serve their sentences, you keep
them on the grounds of the prison in a
in a mobile home where they're semifree.
They're not in the prison. There's no
count time. you know, they can't be
punished additionally, but they're not
allowed outside the the gates, outside
the walls. And here, you're right, the
idea that she was bumped up to a to a
dorm, which is a reward that you get,
right? You leave an actual cell, you go
into a dorm, dorm has TVs all around,
you're free to come and go. You get that
as a reward. And the fact that she got
it just doesn't make any sense to me.
Well, I wrote a book called The Franklin
Scandal, and there were two primary
pimps that were involved. Actually,
Epstein in many ways is a carbon copy of
the Franklin Scandal. And there was one
pimp that was kind of analogous to
Epstein. He had all the connections and
he was he was a power broker. He lived
in DC, had a mansion, all his he was a
CIST. All his rooms were wired for audio
visual blackmail. a lot of the same
attributes that uh that Epstein has. And
he committed suicide and I do believe
that he committed suicide on the
internet it says that he was suicided.
Um
>> no
>> I but I think I think that he said was
given you know an offer he couldn't
refuse. There was a veto corleó
character that came up to him and said
either you kill yourself or we'll kill
you. So I think that that is what
happened in that situation. Now the
other guy, Lawrence King, he kept his
mouth shut. He saw what happened to
Craig Spence and he kept his mouth shut
and he did 10 years. Wasn't uh indicted
on a single count of child abuse, was
indicted on multiple counts of financial
malfeasants. And he had a no-show job
waiting for him in Alexandria, Virginia
at a BMW dealership. So, I think that
that was the kind of deal that was made
with Glenn Maxwell. You saw what
happened to Epstein. You keep your mouth
shut. We'll take care of you and then
when you get out, we'll take care of
you. We'll continue to take care of you.
But I'm sure that Jeffrey Epstein and
Maxwell, they socked away a lot of
money. I've got no doubts about that to
keep to take care of.
>> I think you're right. Actually, I think
you're right. There's a lot of money
that we're talking about here. hundreds
of millions of dollars uh reportedly.
And I think that that was probably the
deal. The deal was, look, you're going
to have to do some time. We'll work hard
to try to make it as easy a sentence as
possible. And uh and then when you get
out, okay, you can just live in
obscurity, but you have plenty of money.
You can come and go as you please and do
what you want and you know, whatever.
And it didn't really work out that way.
He thought he got away with it in 2006,
2007. And for a while he did, but he
couldn't stop himself because remember
as the APAs have told us, you can't cure
this.
And so, uh, it got the better of him. I
agree with you, though.
>> I think that there was a
>> Go ahead.
>> I was going to say I believe he
committed suicide only because having
done prison time myself, I can tell you
that most of the prison guards have
their heads up their asses. Excuse my
language, but they just do. They're
asleep on the job or they're in the
guard booth looking at porn or playing
solitire or talking to their
girlfriends. These are wash outs from
the local police academy or from the
military who couldn't cut it anywhere
else. Literally the only qualifications
you need to be a prison guard or you
have to be working on a GED or already
have a GED or high school diploma and no
felony convictions. That's it. That's
it. And so you're not getting the cream
of the crop, the best that society has
to offer. So when these guys are
supposed to walk around every eight
minutes or every 15 minutes depending on
the level of security that you're in,
they only do it once every hour or once
every two hours because they're sound
asleep in that guard booth. Well, that's
what you get. You get what you pay for.
Similarly, um the the reports that the
cameras weren't working, the cameras
never work anywhere in all the prisons,
the cameras are down half the time. It
it's because that's just the way it is
and nobody really cares to make sure
that they are working or that they're
upgraded or they're hooked up properly
or they're, you know, they're the latest
that are available. People just don't
care. And so I do believe he committed
suicide. I believe that it was
unfortunate for a whole bunch of
reasons, but I believe it was a suicide.
>> Well, you you talk about Jeffrey
Epstein. I mean, his addiction was off
the charts. He had to have three girls a
day or that's what he he was. I mean, he
had a whole machine that was built by
Maxwell and they those women that worked
for him that recruited girls. I mean,
they kept pumping girls out to him. Uh,
and as I said, three times a day. That
was his goal. Three times a day. But I
think not only was his addiction
getting extreme, but there was also a
lot of media on him. And I think that
that's the other variable. Miami Herald
had published that series and there were
a number of civil lawsuits being
launched at him. So I believe that
Jeffrey Ebstein was a black mailer and
you've lose your efficacy as a black
mailer if everybody knows you're a
blackmailer. And I think that that's
what happened with with Craig Spence,
too, is he started to get too much media
on him. And and I think that ultimately
was the death now for uh Jeffrey Epstein
is the media. Nick, the um the
administration, as as we mentioned a
little while ago, has already said
they're not going to be able to make the
30-day uh limit that they have to
release these documents, but they do say
that they're committed to releasing
everything that they're supposed to
release with redactions, obviously. Do
you expect to see anything that's truly
revoly? Do you expect for for there to
be blockbuster
news that comes out of these subsequent
uh releases?
The Trump administration has let us down
every step of the way. I'm not expecting
a leopard to change its spots at this
point. Um
that document that came out about 1996
though that was somewhat revoly. I'm I'm
glad that that document came out because
there's litigation going on now between
Epstein victims and the FBI and and
that's kind of a smoking gun that the
FBI really just let it slide when it
actually filled out a the there was a
form it wasn't a 302 but it was an
actual investigative form about a child
pornography investigation. So that was
revoly. There's a lot of other documents
that are coming up, but the documents
that we really need, the documents that
are important is everything that went
into that 50 or 60 count indictment in
uh in Florida by the feds. Those
documents are very important and we
haven't got any any meaningful
information from from those documents.
H [sighs]
you know they I I say this all the time
but in business school they teach you
that hope is not a strategy.
Do we have anything more than just hope
that DOJ does the right thing and
releases everything to the point where
maybe people who have committed very
serious crimes against children can be
prosecuted for those crimes? Or are we
past that already?
Well, I'm the director of Epstein
Justice and what we want is an
independent congressional commission and
that would not require any kind of
executive oversight. And independent
congressional commissions often use
citizens that are not affiliated with
the government to investigate and be
part of it. Uh if this was just going to
go to a subcommittee, it would die. But
I think an independent congressional
commission is the way to go. Ultimately,
we don't even need very many documents.
Uh, a lot of the documents that we need
are out there. Uh, and we know who the
procurers are. We know who the procurers
are and we know who a lot of the perks
are. And we've got at least 1,200
victims.
If the Department of Justice wanted to
get indictments in this, it would be
like it would be a simple RICO case,
>> right? They would go to the procurers.
Those procurers are guilty of multiple
counts of child trafficking, which is a
heavy sentence. In the federal system,
it's 15 to life. And you can nail them
with 10 counts of child trafficking
because they're guilty of a lot more
than 10. If you I mean, you can go light
and go five counts. they would start
rolling over on the pers. You've got a
lot of witnesses that were molested. So
between the procurers and the documents
that we have and the witnesses, if our
government had a will to start putting
people in prison, we could have done it
a long time ago.
>> Yeah.
>> So I'm not despondent at this point. I
when people said to me, "Yeah, it's the
day approaching and Trump
administration," I wasn't very excited
about it. I I knew that this was going
to happen. I I mean I I've been
following this case too long. And Donald
Trump's behavior in this case has just
been so bizarre. I mean, he's he's
called it a hoax even. So, I wasn't
expecting actually this is exactly what
I was expecting.
But we as Americans, we have to put
pressure on our government and we have
to make our legislators do the right
thing. And our legislators will do the
right thing if there's enough fear. And
it and it and it's up to us as
Americans.
We can either
if you cover up a crime, you're aiding
and betting that crime. So as Americans,
we can coexist with a government that
aids and abetss child trafficking, child
sexual trafficking, or we can make sure
our government doesn't do that. And it's
it's really I think it's ultimately
going to be up to us the body politic to
make sure that our government doesn't
aid in a bad child traff. And it's
really unfortunate that the government
has descended to such depths that not
only to be part of it but to cover it
up. But that's the way it is and we but
as Americans we have to we have to flush
our system out. I Americans know that
something is seriously wrong with their
political system and and they've known
it for quite a bit. And I think that's
why Donald Trump became president. There
was a [clears throat] real populist
demand for someone who was going wasn't
going to be politics as usual. Americans
are very tired of politics as usual. And
what we see in Trump is what we've seen
previously from other administrations
with certainly with regards to Ebstein.
>> Nick, tell us um what you're writing
these days and where people can go to
learn more about the work that you're
doing.
I am the director of Epstein justice as
I said earlier and I'm working very very
hard to advance Epstein justice and what
we're doing is you can go to our our
website epstejjustice.com we're having
uh monthly webinars and then we're
organizing people by state via Facebook
and
we're going to keep we keep growing and
growing uh it's it's tough I and we're
all volunteers. Um, but as as we keep
growing, we need uh we need resources.
Um, but a lot of people have been very
generous with their time. And
I'm I'm very happy at this point the way
that we're going to grow. We're I know
that we're going to pick up more
momentum as more Americans get
disillusioned
by what the Trump administration is
doing. And actually,
in all fairness to Donald Trump, I mean,
Joseph Biden didn't do anything about
it. Barack Obama didn't do anything
about it. And uh Bush too was the one
that really started the cover up.
Although you can make an argument for
Clinton u because of the 1996 FBI
reports.
>> Well, thank you very much for being with
us and thanks for trying to shed a light
on all these uh these different issues
and on the documents themselves. But I I
suspect we have a long way to go before
we really have uh have answers to this u
this very difficult and really horrible
case. Thanks for helping us.
>> No problem. And I'm sure you and I will
be talking about this again.
>> I suspect we will probably sooner rather
than later. Yeah, I think you're right.
Thanks for being with us.
>> Take care, John.
>> Ladies and gentlemen, thanks again for
joining us for another episode of Deep
Focus. We can only do this because of
you. It's because you have liked, you
have shared, you have commented, you
have subscribed. That's really important
to us. And please, please keep it up.
Please especially subscribe and help us
get the word out to many, many more
people. Thanks for being with us. I'm
John Kuryako. We'll see you next time on
Deep Focus. Bye-bye.